Right before the Chuseok holidays…
秋夕节到来之际…
I'm sorry I was late. There was heavy traffic.
很抱歉我来迟了 堵车太严重了
No, it's fine. I just came out too.
没关系 我也刚出门
Hey, my cousin got married pretty late.
喂 我表弟那么大年纪终于结婚了
So everyone at the wedding cried.
所以婚礼上大家都哭了
And my mom packed me food from the buffet.
我妈还给我装了好多自助餐
Look at all this food.
看这么多吃的
Goodness.
天啊
This sure makes us feel like normal people, doesn't it?
这种生活才让我们觉得 自己跟普通人一样 对吧？
I went to a wedding on a Saturday.
我周六去参加婚礼
And we're stuck downtown in the middle of a congested road.
我们被困在市中心堵得水泄不通
It'd be perfect if only we weren't headed to visit someone in prison.
如果我们不是去监狱见人就完美了
Seoul Tollgate announced that cars leaving Seoul…
首尔收费站称离开首尔的车辆…
Hey. How do office workers wear ties every day?
喂 你说上班族天天系领带不烦吗？
This is so suffocating.
真是快勒死了
And the Honam Expressway…
湖南高速…
Gosh. I should've brought some clothes to change into.
真是的 早知道带点换的衣服了
Do you want to switch shoes at least?
你要不要跟我换鞋穿？
No, it's okay.
不用 没事
-Do you want rice cakes? -Sorry?
-要吃年糕吗？ -什么？
-Open your mouth. -I'm good.
-张嘴 -不用了
Open up.
张嘴
There. Chew it.
对了 使劲嚼
That's it.
吃的真香
Let's go.
走了
SEOUL DETENTION CENTER
（首尔拘留所）
Isn't it nice?
是不是很棒？
It does look big and nice.
确实看着又大又好
I spent two months' salary on this. It better be nice.
我花了两个月工资买的 肯定好啊
You're spending more than you're earning.
你现在花的比挣的还多
You need the right tools to put your skills to use.
工欲善其事 必先利其器
Hey, this kind of looks lame.
这种看着就很过时了
I'll put it away.
我放起来了
I'm comfortable with it. Let me use it.
我用习惯这个了 让我用吧
-You want to? -Yes.
-你想用？ -是
-Okay, it's all yours. -Okay.
-行 给你了 -好
All right. Hold on.
好 等一下
This should be…
这个…
Should we put this here?
是不是应该放这里？
KEEP QUIET
（保持安静）
Inmate 4709, you have visitors.
4709号犯人 有人见你
Who's here?
谁啊？
Look at him dusting off his feet again. Gosh.
看他又在拍脚上的灰 真是的
-That fool. -Just go, will you?
-真是个傻子 -你能不能赶紧走啊？
-Jeez. -Seriously.
-真是的
Hurry up. The officer is waiting.
快点吧 狱警还在等着呢
-Goodness. -Come on.
-天啊 -快走
Darn you.
真是的
-I'm sorry, man. -What the…
-不好意思 -怎么…
You can't blindside me like this.
你不能偷袭我
I can't even stand the way he walks.
我连他走路的姿势都受不了
All right.
好了
We're not here to interrogate you, so relax.
我们来这里不是审问你的 放松点
Did you dress up to see me?
你是专门为我打扮的吗？
Why do you ask?
为什么这样问？
I feel special.
受宠若惊
Isn't it all over now?
不是已经结束了吗？
Do you think it's over?
你觉得已经结束了？
You caught me.
你们都抓住我了
Mr. Cho, we still have many questions for you.
赵先生 我们还有很多问题想问你
But I told you everything last time.
可是我上次什么都告诉你们了
I told that lady everything too.
还有那个女士
She is a detective, not a "lady."
她是警察 不是什么“女士”
We want to hear more about you,
我们想听你多说一点
not about the case.
不是说案子
You could tell us about your childhood
你可以告诉我们你的童年
or about what you usually feel.
或者你平时的感受
It's just for our record, so don't worry about it.
我们只是记录用的 所以别担心
Right.
对
Well…
那么…
Is there anything you'd like to tell us?
你有什么想对我们说的吗？
It's okay. You can tell us anything.
没事的 你可以对我们畅所欲言
You're not interrogating me,
你们不是审问我
but you want to hear my story?
而是想听我的故事？
Yes.
对
No one wants to hear my story.
没有人想听我的故事
-Why do you? -We visited your place.
-你们是为什么？ -我们去看了你家
My place?
我家？
Yes, it was very clean.
对 非常干净
Everything was neatly organized,
包括袜子
even your socks.
屋里所有的东西都摆放特别整齐
I don't like it when things are messy.
我不喜欢东西乱糟糟的
I know.
我知道
So you must be having a hard time here.
那你在这里一定过得很不好
Right?
对吗？
Every day, strangers who committed heinous crimes
每天都有犯了各种重罪的陌生人
are eating and sleeping with you.
和你同吃同睡
It must be awful.
一定很痛苦
It is awful.
很痛苦
So…
那么…
why don't you tell us more about yourself?
不如跟我们再讲讲你自己？
The people here will try to treat you as one of them.
这里的犯人们觉得你跟他们一样
But in our eyes,
可是在你看来
you seem a little different.
你跟他们是有点不同的
Well…
那个…
They don't even wash often.
他们都不经常洗漱
They stink, and the cell is small and filthy.
身上都臭了 牢房又小又脏
It's really driving me crazy.
我真的快被逼疯了
Right, I'm sure.
对 我相信你
So this was what we thought.
所以我们觉得
Perhaps you…
也许你…
didn't actually intend to kill Soo-hyun--
本来没打算杀死秀贤
That's right, I…
没错 我…
I never intended to kill her.
我从来没想要杀她
That's why we want to hear your story.
所以我们想听听你的故事
To understand why you're different from the others.
好好了解一下你和别人不同的地方
Looks like you've lost some weight.
你看着好像瘦了
Have you been eating well?
吃得怎么样？
Then why don't we
那不如我们
eat something first before we start talking?
先吃点东西再谈话？
How are you feeling?
你感觉怎么样？
I got to have a proper meal for a change.
早就该好好吃顿饭改变一下了
I wish every day was like today.
真希望每天都能像今天一样
Do you regret it?
你后悔吗？
She shouldn't have been there.
她不应该在那里的
What do you mean by she shouldn't have been there?
你说她不应该在那里是什么意思？
Blame the girl's bad luck.
怪那女孩运气不好
It's Soo-hyun.
秀贤
Her name.
她有名字
Lee Soo-hyun.
李秀贤
Had she not come to that place that day,
如果那天她没有去那个地方
nothing would have happened to her or me.
她和我都不会遇到后来那些事了
Do you think…
你觉得事情变成这样
this incident is her fault?
是她的错？
I'm saying it's her fault for catching my attention.
我说的是怪她吸引了我的注意力
I wonder what was on his mind
真想知道赵贤吉看着
as Cho Hyun-gil was watching such an innocent child.
这么天真的孩子时 脑子里在想什么
Why is he different from us?
为什么他和我们这么不一样？
Are you from Samcheonpo?
你老家是三千浦？
I don't hear a dialect though.
不过我没听出口音来
I moved to Seoul when I was 15.
我15岁就搬到首尔了
In eighth grade?
八年级的时候？
I didn't go to middle school.
我没上中学
I started working after elementary school.
小学毕业就开始工作了
What kind of work?
什么工作？
I worked at factories,
我进过工厂
sold fish, and worked at butcher shops.
卖过鱼 还在肉铺打过工
I did everything I was told to do.
让我做什么我就做什么
I also had many jobs.
我也打过很多工
My family was very poor when I was young.
我小时候家里很穷
Since I'm the eldest son,
我又是长子
I had to help my parents on their farm and sell our harvest.
得帮父母照顾地里的活儿 卖粮食
I did all sorts of things.
我什么都干
Detective, what was your name again?
警官 你叫什么名字？
My name?
我的名字？
I'm Kook Young-soo.
我叫国荣秀
Detective Kook, then did you also quit school after elementary school?
国警官 你也是小学毕业后辍学了吗？
I entered middle school a year later than everyone else.
我比大家晚一年上中学
I see. At least you went to middle school.
知道了 你至少还上中学了
You think you two are different?
你觉得你们俩不是一路人？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
You were both poor, and both of you struggled.
你们家里都穷 也都经历了很多
But he attended middle school, so it's different.
但是他上了中学 所以不是一路人
I could've been different too.
我本来也能不一样的
You think that's why you became a criminal?
你觉得这是你变成罪犯的原因吗？
Because you're a dropout?
因为你辍学了？
Well…
那个…
I…
我…
-Detective. -Yes.
-警官 -是
Can you get me a soda?
你能给我买瓶汽水吗？
I have a habit of drinking one
我习惯每次吃完饭
after every meal.
喝瓶汽水
She shouldn't have been there.
她不应该在那里的
Blame the girl's bad luck.
怪那女孩运气不好
Hey.
喂
-Are you all right? -Of course.
-你还好吗？ -没事
Let's go.
走吧
You quit smoking.
你戒烟了
Yes, what's up?
对 怎么了？
Why do you carry a lighter around?
那为什么随身带着打火机？
Oh, this thing?
哦 这个？
For emergencies.
应急用
I'm sure there will come a day when I'll crave a smoke.
我肯定会有特别想抽根烟的时候
If I don't have a lighter at that time,
如果那会儿没打火机
I may seriously go crazy.
我可能真的要疯了
PROPOSAL
（企划书）
We just got started,
我们才刚开始
so let us do this for just one more year.
就让我们再干一年吧
Go ahead.
盖章吧
We won't cause any trouble.
我们不会捣乱的
Right here. Please.
就在这儿 拜托了
So please… Help me out.
拜托了…帮帮我
Sit down.
坐下
-Goodness. -Just one more year.
-天啊 -再给我们一年吧
This year's college entrance exam must have been easy.
今年的高考一定很简单
-Arms down. -The cut-off scores.
-胳膊放下来 -分数线
They went up by as much as ten points.
提高了十分
-Reported by Lee Yong-nam. -Done.
-李勇南报道 -好了
The college exam score cut-off
首尔大学人文系的
for SNU's Humanities Department…
高考分数线…
-Salute! -We'll do our best!
-敬礼 -我们一定会努力的
JANUARY 2001
（2001年1月）
MARCH 2001
（2001年3月）
MAY 2001
（2001年5月）
A terrorist attack on the US put Americans and people around the world
美国遭遇的恐怖袭击事件 使全美国和全世界人民
in great shock.
为之震惊
SEPTEMBER 2001
（2001年9月）
One second.
等一下
OCTOBER 2001
（2001年10月）
NOVEMBER 2001
（2001年11月）
DECEMBER 2001
（2001年12月）
-Excuse me. -One second.
-借过 -等一下
DECEMBER 2001
（2001年12月）
JANUARY 2002
（2002年1月）
-Yes. -If you give us one more chance,
-是 -如果你再给我们一次机会
we'll repay with good results.
我们一定会用优秀成绩作为回报
Yes, sir.
是的
EXTENDED BY ONE YEAR
（延长一年）
-Thank you!
-谢谢你
-Go, Korea! Hey! -Go, Korea!
-韩国 加油 喂 -韩国 加油
All right!
太好了
NOVEMBER 2002
（2002年11月）
Good grief!
可恶
Hey, let him go. Officer!
喂 让他走吧 狱警
You can take him away.
你可以把他带走了
Darn it.
该死
DECEMBER 2002
（2002年12月）
I'm aware.
我知道
So why did you go that far and commit that crime?
所以你为什么会走到犯罪那一步？
My gosh, these detectives.
真是的 这些警察
NEW HOPE!
（新希望 2003年）
Although the temperature is below zero,
虽然气温低至零度以下
the beach is filled with people waiting for the first sunrise.
人们依然挤满了海滩 等待观赏第一次日出
I got some steamed buns.
我买了包子
The number of people…
人数…
FEBRUARY 2003
（2003年2月）
MARCH 2003
（2003年3月）
APRIL 2003
（2003年4月）
JULY 2003
（2003年7月）
AUGUST 2003
（2003年8月）
It's been so long since our last team dinner.
好久都没有团队聚餐了
Eat up while you can. A day like this may never come again.
多吃点 这种日子 可能以后都没机会了
Eat up. I'll do it.
你吃吧 我来弄
It's fine. I'm an expert at grilling, so I never let anyone else do it.
没事 我可是烧烤高手 所以我从来不让别人插手
-Let me show you my skills. Give it to me. -No, sir.
-让我来给你展示我的技术 给我 -不要
Just eat this. It's hot.
来吃一口 小心烫
It's good.
真好吃
Please evaluate my skills.
请评价一下我的技术吧
-I'll eat it myself. -My gosh.
-我自己来吧 -真是的
-You should eat too. -Okay.
-你也吃 -好
All right.
来
Let's continue to do well.
大家继续努力
Okay.
好
-Great work. -Bottoms up.
-大家辛苦了 -干杯
Weather newsflash.
天气快报
The typhoon is heading north,
台风正向北移动
making many parents worry as they wait for their children.
很多父母一边等待一边担心着孩子们
Typhoon 14, also known as Maemi,
14号台风 也叫鸣蝉
will cause strong winds to blow
将在全国范围形成强风
along with heavy rain throughout the entire country.
同时带来暴雨
The wind speed of Maemi
鸣蝉的风速
can reach up to 60m per second.
可高达每秒60米
It first headed to Taiwan, then suddenly changed course
起初台风方向是中国台湾 随后突然改变方向
toward the Korean Peninsula.
向朝鲜半岛袭来
Honey, I'm home.
老婆 我回来了
What…
怎么…
No…
不…
Honey!
老婆
What's…
怎么会…
-There's another one. -No, wait…
-又有一个 -不 等…
I WAS SO ANGRY
（我非常气愤）
BECAUSE SHE DIED BEFORE I COULD DO ANYTHING
（因为我什么都还没做 她就死了）
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
So do you know who the new chief is?
你知道新来的股长是谁吗？
Sorry?
什么？
Right.
对
What's wrong? What's with that face?
怎么了？怎么这副表情？
Oh, you're here.
你来了
Hey, good morning, Tae-gu.
早上好啊 泰九
Have you been well?
过得好吗？
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我？
You could've at least given me a heads-up.
至少提醒我一下啊
Everyone already knew.
大家都已经知道了
I didn't need to do that.
我就不用提醒你了
Except for me, who has to take orders from him.
除了要听他发号施令的我不知道
I mean, I thought…
不是啦 我以为…
you already knew too.
你肯定也知道
Okay.
好
-Goodness, hello. -Sir.
-天啊 你们好 -你好
I'm Kim Bong-sik, the new chief of the Special Crime Squad.
我是金奉植 机搜队的新股长
-Hello. -Nice to meet you.
-很高兴认识你
I hope we all get along.
希望大家相处愉快
-Yes. -It's nice to meet you.
-是 -很高兴认识你
Let's grab some soju.
有空一起喝烧酒
-Sure. -Okay.
-好
If you knew Kim Bong-sik was coming as our new chief,
如果你们知道金奉植要来当新股长
you of all people could've let me know.
你是最应该跟我说的
I thought it would only bother you if I told you ahead of time.
我觉得如果我提前告诉你 只会让你心烦
Also, nothing would change anyway.
而且反正也不会改变什么
Nothing could be changed,
不会改变什么
so I should be kept in the dark?
我就要被蒙在鼓里吗？
No, that's not what I meant.
不是的 我不是那个意思
Well…
好吧…
I'm sorry.
对不起
There's no need for you to apologize.
你不用道歉
Forget it.
没事
It probably wasn't easy for you either.
估计你心里也不好受
Does the Analysis Team know?
分析小组的人知道吗？
The Analysis Team?
分析小组？
Back when they were at Jungbu Station,
以前在中部警察局的时候
I heard Song Ha-young once screwed over Chief Kim Bong-sik.
我听说宋霞永有次整了金奉植股长
People in this field really love rumors,
这行的人真的很喜欢那些流言蜚语
don't they?
是吧？
RAPE AND MUTILATION MURDERER HWANG DAE-SUN
（强奸及肢解谋杀犯 黄大善）
Why are you back?
你们怎么又来了？
We still do not understand
黄先生 我们还是不明白
why you committed these crimes, Mr. Hwang.
你为什么犯下那些罪行
So we came to hear the story of your life, Mr. Hwang.
所以我们想来听你讲讲你的人生故事
What story?
什么故事？
Well, can you share stories of your childhood?
你可以讲讲你的童年经历吗？
Why do you want to hear my sad childhood story?
你们为什么想听我悲惨的童年经历？
I guess you have lots of bad memories.
看来你有很多不美好的回忆
In that case,
既然如此
can you tell me one thing that made you the angriest?
你可以告诉我让你最愤怒的事吗？
It's my dad.
是我爸爸
He always beat me up without a reason.
他总是无缘无故打我
He'd beat me up during meals, and beat me for going to school.
吃饭的时候打 去上学也要打
I sometimes took a few days off
有时候打得太狠
because he hurt me so badly.
只能躺在床上 也去不了学校
I was also stripped down to my underwear
我还被脱了内衣
and got kicked out of the house.
被撵到屋外
I stood by the front gate.
就站在大门口
So if your neighborhood friends saw you,
如果被邻居的朋友看到了
they would've teased you a lot.
他们肯定经常取笑你
Kids made fun of me
小孩子们取笑我
until I went to middle school.
一直到我上中学
I'd beat them up too.
他们都会群殴我
I never hung out with them.
我一直都没办法融入他们
Those emotions must have been tough on you.
这些感觉肯定让你很难受
It's humiliating to be stripped.
被脱了衣服是很丢人的事
How did you usually deal with your anger?
你通常会怎么处理愤怒情绪？
There wasn't much I could do as a kid.
我那时候还是个孩子 没多少办法
All I could do was kill animals.
只能弄死一些不会说话的动物
I killed my neighbor's cow with a sickle.
我用镰刀杀了邻居的牛
I caught a dog in my neighborhood and watched it jump and bark
我在家附近抓到一条狗 看着它
in hot, boiling water.
在开水里乱跳乱叫
Watching that got me off.
那种场面会让我心里舒服点
My dad stripped me and kicked me out so many times.
我爸爸把我脱光衣服撵出去太多次了
So I still hate it when my body is exposed.
所以我现在依然很讨厌露出身体
It infuriates me.
我会很愤怒
No matter how hot it is, I never wear shorts or short sleeves.
天气再热 我从来不穿短裤或者短袖
After you killed animals,
你杀死动物后
did you dismember them too?
还会肢解它们吗？
Sometimes.
偶尔
I tried cutting them up.
我想把他们剁碎
I learned to cook at a restaurant.
我在餐厅当过学徒
Using a knife to cut them into pieces was fun.
用刀把他们剁碎感觉很好玩
Your second female victim.
你的第二位女性受害者
Is that why you cut off the flesh on her leg
你强奸并谋杀她之后 就是因此
after you raped and murdered her?
割下她腿上的一块肉吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
I wanted to cut it off when she was alive.
我本来想趁她活着割肉的
But she kept moving, and her blood splattered.
可是她一直动 而且血溅的到到处都是
So I stopped for a bit.
所以我停了一会儿
After I killed her,
杀死她之后
I sat next to her and tried to cut it off again.
我坐在她旁边 再割了一次
But I don't remember much because I was drunk.
不过我喝醉了 所以记不太清楚了
Then you took it home.
然后你把那块肉带回家
But no one saw you?
没有人发现吗？
It was dripping in blood.
上边还在滴血
I bet it must've scared people.
我猜肯定会吓着别人的
Why? They wouldn't know what it was.
为什么？他们又不知道那是什么
I thought it was meat for a second
我第二天刚醒那会儿
when I woke up the next day.
还以为就是一块肉呢
You don't remember?
你不记得了？
Or do you not want to talk to us?
还是不想告诉我们？
It's both.
都有
Do I have to tell you everything?
我一定要把所有事情都告诉你们吗？
You said it wasn't an interrogation.
你不说是这不是审讯吗？
GWANGJU PRISON
（光州监狱）
-Have a good day. -You too.
-再见
Hwang Dae-sun definitely shows the behaviors of serial killers.
黄大善的行为 完全符合连环杀手的特征
Right. But why do you think he cut off the flesh on her leg?
对 不过你觉得他为什么 要把她腿上的肉割下一块？
It looks like he didn't know.
好像他自己也不知道
I think his rage against his abusive father
我觉得是他对虐待狂父亲的愤怒
developed into abnormal sexual behaviors.
发展成了不正常的性行为
Then his rage caused him to mutilate the body too.
也是这种愤怒导致他肢解尸体
Right.
对
Many organizations are trying to support flood victims
台风鸣蝉对朝鲜半岛造成严重损失
from Typhoon Maemi which struck the Korean Peninsula pretty hard.
很多企业纷纷向 因台风造成的洪水灾民伸出援手
The civil organizations…
民间组织…
How may I help you?
请问你有什么事吗？
Is this the Behavioral Analysis Team?
这里就是犯罪行为分析小组吗？
-Yes. -Where's Song Ha-young?
-是的 -宋霞永呢？
Inspector Song? He's out for an interview.
宋警官？他出去采访了
"Inspector"?
“警官”？
Should I tell him you stopped by when he comes back?
要不要等他回来 我跟他交代一下你来过？
SKY, WIND, STAR, AND POETRY BY YUN DONG-JU
（《天、风、星星和诗》 诗人尹东柱）
He hasn't changed.
他还是老样子
What brings you here?
你来有什么事吗？
Don't mind me.
不用管我
Get back to work.
你忙你的
It's like nothing ever happened. This isn't fair.
好像什么都没发生过一样 脸皮真厚
Sorry?
什么意思？
The weather.
我说天气
The weather being this nice isn't fair.
天气这么好真是不公平
The pain and sense of loss.
那种痛苦和失落感
The suffering
那种痛苦
is only up to the victims to bear.
只有受害者在承受
I bet some people are enjoying this good weather.
我猜一定有人正在享受好天气
All right.
好吧
He's not even investigating the case.
他又不能调查案件
Why is he reading the case reports for the detectives?
看警察的案件报告干吗？
Seriously. This nosy jerk.
真是的 多管闲事的混蛋
Hey. I'll tell him when he comes--
喂 等他回来我会告诉他…
You punk!
小子
"Hey"?
“喂”？
Read what it says on my business card.
看看我的名片上写的是什么？
"Special Crime Squad Chief, Kim Bong-sik."
“机搜队股长金奉植”
Are you blind?
你瞎了吗？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
You seem to have picked up bad habits from Song Ha-young.
看来你也学了宋霞永的臭毛病
You're still wet behind your ears.
还是个乳臭未干的臭小子呢
This is the Behavioral Analysis Team's office.
这里是犯罪行为分析小组办公室
You need to tell me why you are here.
请告诉我你到底来这里有什么事
You are going to make me repeat myself.
非要让我再说一遍
You just mind your own business!
管好你自己的事就行了
I'm back.
我回来了
Assistant Inspector Song.
宋警官 你好啊
I hear you're an inspector now.
我听说你现在升到警官了
Inspector Song.
宋警官
Goodness. You seem well.
天啊 你看着不错
What do you guys do here?
你们在这里是干什么的啊？
Why are you dressed up?
怎么穿这么正式？
Why are you here?
你怎么来了？
I don't expect you to give me a warm welcome.
我没期待你能热烈欢迎我
But it's only polite to say hello when you see someone.
但是见面说你好是基本礼仪啊
Don't you agree?
你说是不是？
Seriously. This team is full of rude punks.
真是的 这个组全是没礼貌的臭小子
I'm Statistics Analyst Jung Woo-ju.
我是统计分析师郑宇宙
Statistics analyst?
统计分析师？
You guys have difficult titles here.
你们的名号整这么长
Dumb people won't be able to remember them.
脑袋笨的可记不住
What was it called?
叫什么来着？
Right. A profiler.
对 侧写师
If you're here to talk to me,
如果你是来找我的
let's talk outside.
那就出去说
I have nothing to say to you in private.
我跟你没什么私人话题可说
I just wanted to come to say hello.
我只是过来打个招呼
And I wanted to check out what you do here.
看看你们在这里做什么
Why is the door open? Did…
门怎么开着？有人…
It's been a while, Captain Kook.
国组长 好久不见啊
I was transferred to the Special Crime Squad.
我被调到机搜队了
We'll be seeing each other often. I look forward to working with you.
以后要经常见面了 真期待跟你共事
-Okay. -It was nice to see everyone.
-好 -见到大家真高兴
Right. I bought this for you.
对了 我给你带了这个
I almost forgot.
差点忘了
You still eat chocolates
你还像个小孩子一样
like a little kid, right?
喜欢吃巧克力 对吧？
Even if we don't want to, you'll see me every day.
再不情愿 以后也要天天见了
Let's put our past behind us.
过去的事就让它过去吧
See you around.
回见了
Who was that?
那家伙是谁啊？
Just as I heard, he's one rude cop.
他和传闻一样 真的没教养
I was wondering how great his career was going
那个一成不变的混蛋
after he stabbed me, his mentor, in the back.
能干得多风生水起呢
You've got to be kidding me. An inspector?
警卫算什么？受不了
NOVEMBER 1996
（1996年11月）
Search every nook and cranny of the neighborhood.
附近每一个角落缝隙都要仔细搜
He's wearing a black jacket with a hoodie and black sneakers.
他穿着黑色夹克 连帽衫和黑色运动鞋
Find him now!
赶快找到他
I'm chasing a suspicious man who fits the description.
我正在追踪一个符合描述的嫌疑人
I'm sorry. I lost him.
对不起 我跟丢了
Yoon Tae-gu, where are you?
尹泰九 你在哪里？
Where are you?
你在哪里？
Let go of me, you bastard.
放开我 你这个混蛋
Darn it.
该死
Jung Soo-chan.
郑秀灿
You're under arrest
你因涉嫌
for robbery, murder, and fleeing.
盗窃 谋杀和逃逸被捕了
You have the right to consult an attorney.
你有权咨询律师
-And to remain silent. -Get him!
-也有权保持沉默 -抓住他
Did you catch him?
你抓住他了？
Gosh. You really are a detective now.
天啊 你终于成为真正的警察了
Hey. We got him.
喂 我们抓住了
Don't stand there. Get him.
别站着了 快抓住他
Yoon Tae-gu caught Jung Soo-chan.
尹泰九抓住了郑秀灿
Nice, Detective Yoon.
干得好 尹刑警
She got him.
她抓住他了
This punk.
这个混蛋
You set an example
你迅速逮捕
for your fellow officers by promptly arresting
一名犯下残忍罪行后逃逸的
a robbery and murder suspect
抢劫谋杀嫌疑人
who was on the run after committing a brutal crime.
为同事们树立了榜样
Hence, I hereby award Inspector Yoon Tae-gu.
因此我特此嘉奖尹泰九警官
JUNGBU POLICE STATION SPECIAL PROMOTION CEREMONY
（中部警察局 特别晋升仪式）
Yoon Tae-gu!
尹泰九
-You're amazing. -Tae-gu, you rock.
-你太厉害了 -泰九 你太牛了
-Well done! -Go, Yoon Tae-gu!
-好样的 -加油 尹泰九
Oh, my. You really look like a cop now.
天啊 你现在看着还真像个警察了
I thought she wouldn't last and get married.
我还以为她会熬不下来 回去结婚呢
-Gosh. She looks great. -You'll be the commissioner in no time.
-天啊 她看着真不错 -要不了多久你都能当厅长了
-Tae-gu can definitely do that. -Of course.
-泰九肯定能做到 -当然了
Could you take a photo of us?
你能给我们拍张照吗？
-Sure. -Can we join?
-当然 -大家一起吗？
You got a special promotion thanks to Ha-young.
你能特别晋升全靠宋霞永
I'm surprised you're holding out well, Tae-gu.
你竟然出乎意料地撑过来了 尹泰九
Okay, let's try that one more time.
好了 再来一张
Nice. All right, smile.
很好 好了 都笑一笑
Okay.
好
Captain.
组长
-Captain Yoon. -Yes?
-尹组长 -怎么了？
Superintendent Baek wants to see you.
白俊植科长想见你
Superintendent Baek? Why?
白科长？什么事？
I have no idea.
我也不知道
He asked for Chief Kim Bong-sik too, but I don't know where he is.
他也让喊金奉植股长过去 可是我不知道他在哪儿
Cheers.
干杯
It's nice to have you back.
我很开心你能回来
Seeing you're the only one welcoming me,
要不是还有你欢迎我
I'm not sure whether I've been doing well so far.
我都不确定我到底混得怎么样
Come on.
什么啊
I really meant it. Do you have to twist my words like that?
我是真心的 你非要曲解我的话吗？
What you need is my intel, not me.
你需要的是我的情报 不是我
That's what makes you indispensable.
情报才是大哥啊
Anyway, pretend not to know me when you see me at the station.
算了吧 去警察局要假装不认识我
Goodness. Don't worry.
天啊 别担心了
Life is full of irony.
生活处处是讽刺啊
Song Ha-young and even Yoon Tae-gu.
宋霞永 还有尹泰九
Who knew I'd meet them again here?
谁能想到我在这里又和他们见面了？
Is this fate or something?
这就是命中注定吧？
Did you meet Inspector Song Ha-young?
你见过宋霞永警卫了吗？
I did.
见过
I can't figure out what his team does.
我实在搞不懂他那个团队在干什么
When you stab someone in the back, it all comes back--
我是没见过背后捅人刀子还混得好…
Darn it. There's one exception.
该死 不过有一个例外
Who? You?
谁？你？
You little…
你这个小…
The head prosecutor
部长检察官
who asked for Yoon Tae-gu back then.
那时候点名要尹泰九的那个
HEAD PROSECUTOR LEE DONG-JU
（部长检察官 李东柱）
Here.
给你
It's classified information, so don't reveal your source.
这是保密信息 所以别跟人说哪来的
Investigate it alone, quietly.
自己悄悄调查
-This is credible, right? -Have I ever lied to you?
-这资料是可靠的吧？ -我什么时候骗过你？
Go through it. There's solid evidence too.
好好看看 里边还有可靠证据
Why did I miss all this?
我怎么都不知道这个？
Yoon Tae-gu is one of your direct reports, right?
尹泰九是你的直接下属吧？
Yes, sir.
是的
-Hello. -Where is Room 10?
-你好 -10号房间在哪里？
It's this way. You'll find it on your left.
这边走 左手边就是
Yoon Tae-gu.
尹泰九
I mean, Detective Yoon.
我是说尹刑警
We're now getting the hang of working together as a team,
我们现在作为团队合作很默契
and you worked hard on this case, so I want to buy you a drink.
你负责这个案子也辛苦了 我想请你喝一杯
Come meet me here.
来这里见我吧
-I'm telling you. -My goodness.
-我没骗你 -天啊
There she is. Come on in.
她来了 快进来吧
You made it. Take a seat.
你来了 坐吧
Come on. Take a seat.
过来坐吧
Come on!
过来啊
Hey, where are you going?
喂 你去哪儿？
"Schmoozing"?
“招待”？
-Goodness, the station is a hot mess. -How dare you disgrace the police force?
-天啊 局里都乱成这样了 -你竟然敢丢警察的脸？
-Detective Yoon, you're something. -Are you satisfied?
-尹刑警 真有你的 -你满意了吗？
The head prosecutor
点名要尹泰九的
who asked for Yoon Tae-gu back then?
部长检察官？
I ended up taking bribes
我后来违心
from a building contractor against my will.
收了一个建筑承包商的贿赂
And arrested a fake suspect.
还逮捕了一个假嫌疑人
Due to that, I was branded a corrupt cop.
因为这个我还被起外号叫贪污警察
Everything was set up so he'd look like the real culprit.
一切都安排那么好 他看着就是真凶
Anyone would've been tricked.
谁都可能被骗的
Song Ha-young didn't!
宋霞永就没有被骗
That punk really gets on my nerves.
那个混蛋真是我的冤家
He has to get in the way of everything I do.
不管我做什么 他都要冒出来挡道
I got demoted because of him!
我就是因为他才被降职了
But you're back now.
可是你现在回来了
Song Ha-young was branded
宋霞永被人叫做背叛自己上司
a backstabbing troublemaker who betrays his superiors.
引发内部矛盾的刺头
That's why he's working in that dump of an office now.
所以他现在只能在那个 垃圾堆一样的办公室工作
That's not enough.
这还没完
He acts like a gentleman to your face but skims the cream off the top
他当面老老实实地装绅士
behind your back.
背后抢功劳
-Everyone needs to know that. -Bong-sik.
-应该让大家都知道他的真面目 -大哥
I'll only trust Chief Kim Bong-sik, who's back in Seoul now.
我只相信重回 首尔警察局的金奉植股长
Why would you trust me?
你为什么要相信我？
Don't trust anyone.
不要相信任何人
Goodness, you're hurting my feelings.
天啊 你真是伤人
-You don't even trust me? -You little…
-你连我都不相信？ -你这混蛋
By the way,
对了
the Suseong-dong case in Gangnam.
江南区寿城洞案
Who is the victim?
受害者是谁？
Those at Gangnam Police Station are keeping it quiet.
江南区警察局的人嘴巴很紧
Hey, today is my first day.
喂 我今天第一天上班
You must've heard something.
你肯定多少听说了一些东西
Can I please eat first?
能先让我吃口饭再说吗？
Captain Yoon, you're here.
尹组长 你来了
-I heard you asked for me. -What? You came alone?
-听说你想见我 -怎么回事？就你过来了？
Bong-sik isn't at his desk?
金奉植不在办公桌吗？
We must be ready to mobilize at all times.
我们警察要随时待命的啊
But he can't be reached on his first day?
他第一天上班就联系不上？
Darn it.
真是的
We need you to take on a case.
我们需要你接一个案子
The victim is Han Seok-hoon a professor at Hankuk University.
受害者是韩国大学教授韩世勋
He and his wife were murdered in their home two weeks ago.
两周前他们夫妻俩在家中遇害
MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG CASE REPORT
（寿城洞60多岁老夫妇谋杀案报告）
We need you to work on it.
我们需要你调查这个案子
It belongs to Gangnam Station.
这是江南警察局的案子
It does fall under their jurisdiction,
确实是他们辖区的
but he's related to someone who is very high up.
可是他是高层某个人的家人
I was asked to look into it quietly, so that's all I know.
我接到通知要暗中调查 我只知道这些了
But I think they're struggling to find leads.
不过我觉得他们没找到线索
How do I find a phone number?
怎么查找电话号码啊？
I think the reporters already caught a whiff of it.
我觉得记者们已经得到消息了
The higher-ups want us
高层想让我们
to prevent media coverage and work on it swiftly.
避免惊动媒体 迅速着手调查
Gangnam Police Station will help you out.
江南区警察局会协助你的
Okay.
好
-I'll be off, then. -Okay.
-那我先走了 -好
There, I found it.
在这 我找到了
Look at this.
看看啊
This bastard, Kim Bong-sik. He's not picking up.
这个混蛋金奉植 不接电话
Is it an important case?
是重要的案子吗？
All homicide cases are equally important.
谋杀案没有不重要的
That's true.
确实
Why are we working on another station's case?
为什么要我们调查其他局的案子？
We should go there first.
我们得先去看看
-Chief Kim still isn't at his desk? -No.
-金股长还没归位吗？ -没有
People really don't change.
人真是本性难移
SEPTEMBER 29, 2003
（2003年9月29日）
Are we leaving now? Just the two of us?
我们现在就去吗？就我们两个？
GUNGOK-DONG, JONGNO SEPTEMBER 24, 2003
（钟路区郡谷洞 2003年9月24日）
REPORTING THE MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG AS FOLLOWS
（寿城洞老夫妇谋杀案报告如下）
Damn it, Im Moo-sik that scumbag…
该死 林武植那个混蛋
MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG CASE REPORT
（寿城洞60多岁老夫妇谋杀案报告）
The victims of the murder are a couple in their sixties in Suseong-dong.
寿城洞谋杀案60多岁的受害者
Han Seok-hoon,
是韩国大学教授
a Hankuk University professor, and his wife.
韩世勋和他的妻子
I bet there's something about Han Seok-hoon.
我猜是韩世勋出事了
Gosh, seriously.
天啊 真是的
I told you not to say the victim's name.
我跟你说了别说受害者的名字
Come on. You need to give me something to write about.
拜托了 你得给我点东西让我写报道
Loyalty isn't a one-way street.
就我一个人一直闭口不谈？
They've been preserving the scene for over two weeks now.
他们都在现场两个多星期了
There's definitely something.
肯定是有什么大新闻
You're really telling me nothing?
你真的什么都不跟我说吗？
Over here.
这边
Good day. I'm Yoon Tae-gu from Seoul HQ.
你们好 我是首尔总部的尹泰九
-This is… -Nam Il-young, also from HQ.
-这位是… -南日永 也是总部的
Yes, I got a call. This way.
对 我接到通知了 这边
-Okay. -Hey, tidy up here.
-好 -喂 整理一下
There was cash lying around, but he didn't even touch it.
这些现金这么显眼 可他碰都没碰
They think it's an act of resentment masked as a burglary.
他们认为是伪装成入室盗窃的仇杀
It's clean.
很干净呢
The victims were overpowered
受害者没有任何抵抗
without any sort of resistance.
应该是一击毙命
If they had resisted,
如果他们有过抵抗
blood would've splattered to the ceiling as he was swinging his weapon.
凶手挥舞凶器时 血会溅到天花板
You'll see that the victims' bodies are clean
等会儿去停尸房 你就能发现
with no sign of defense when you get to the morgue later.
受害者的身体很干净 没有抵抗痕迹
Gosh, I don't know what this horrifying guy hit them with.
天啊 真不知道 这个可怕的家伙用什么凶器作的案
We're trying our best but weren't able to identify it yet.
我们找了那么久 还没能找到他作案时的凶器
He came into a rich house like this
他进入这么豪华的房子
and only pretended to look for cash.
假装翻箱倒柜却没有拿走一分
It has to be a grudge.
一定是仇杀了
We looked into that, but that seems highly unlikely.
我们也调查那个了 几乎没可能
Both husband and wife had great reputations.
这夫妻俩名声很好
They were high up the social ladder.
他们的社会地位这么高
So they may have incurred a grudge from someone without knowing.
有可能无意间招致别人怨恨
So it may be the doings of an acquaintance holding a grudge?
所以有可能是怀恨在心的熟人作案？
Should we start around the school?
我们是不是可以先从学校开始查？
We already did.
我们已经查过了
Even if it's an act of resentment,
就算是仇杀
his method is too bold and violent.
凶手的手法也过于张狂暴力
Overkilling is common
过度杀戮
among murderers targeting acquaintances.
在针对熟人作案的谋杀案里很常见
I doubt that a mentally ill person
如果是精神有问题的人
would've casually walked into a house like this.
应该不会这么随意地进入这种房子
Could you give us the list of acquaintances you interviewed?
可以把你们采访过的 熟人名单给我们一份吗？
Yes, I will.
好
Once you get the list, check to see if there's anyone
拿到名单后去查一下有前科
with a record and mental illness.
和精神疾病的人
Yes, ma'am.
好
Why did a detective from Seoul HQ come to a case in Gangnam?
为什么首尔总部的刑警 来管江南区的案子？
Yes, sir?
喂 局长？
Hey! Didn't I tell you to release it first?
喂 我不是跟你说了要抢首发？
An article has been released identifying the Suseong-dong victim
已经有人报道了说寿城洞受害者
as Professor Han Seok-hoon!
是韩世勋教授
What?
什么？
You try to be respectful,
你想做到尊重
conscientious, and even loyal.
良知还有忠诚
So when do you plan on getting an exclusive?
那你准备什么时候做到独家啊？
Who wrote that article?
那篇报道是谁写的？
Who do you think? It's Im Moo-sik, of course.
你觉得呢？当然是林武植了
Damn! That son of a bitch.
该死 那个混蛋
Let's hurry on over.
我们赶紧过去
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD, CHIEF KIM BONG-SIK
（机动搜查队一科 股长 金奉植）
Thank you, Bong-sik.
谢谢你 大哥
Kook Young-soo.
国荣秀
SENIOR INSPECTOR, KOOK YOUNG-SOO
（警监 国荣秀）
Gosh, so this is it.
可恶 就是这些东西
INVESTIGATION RECORD
（调查记录）
Having us waste our time by giving us useless things to do.
给我们一堆没用东西 浪费我们时间
The things these higher-ups come up with from their heads…
上边人脑子里怎么想的这些主意…
What about our heads?
我们的脑子怎么了？
I mean it's always so useful.
我是说总是很有用
What's with this report? You didn't even try.
这个报告怎么回事？一点都没用心啊
Be more descriptive.
再写详细点
MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG
（寿城洞60多岁老夫妇谋杀案报告）
Did you talk to Captain Yoon?
你跟尹组长聊过吗？
I'm sure she's doing just fine.
她肯定没事的
It's best for superiors to just stand back and do nothing.
上面的人好好待着就是帮大忙了
Are you talking about me?
你在说我吗？
Gosh, of course not.
当然不是了
Some punk must have leaked the case.
肯定是哪个混蛋泄露了案件信息
The reporters are already on it.
记者已经刊发报道了
Those damn reporters. They sure are fast.
那些可恶的记者 手太快了
Seriously?
这什么啊？
They're coming!
他们来了
Still no leads in Han Seok-hoon's case?
韩世勋案还是没有线索吗？
Out of resentment?
是仇杀吗？
Are you done interviewing?
你采访完了吗？
-Do you have a suspect? -Were any valuables stolen?
-你们有嫌疑人了吗？ -有贵重物品被偷吗？
Is it an acquaintance's doing?
是熟人作案吗？
Answer us, please!
请回答我们
HWANG DAE-SUN SECOND INTERVIEW REPORT
（黄大善二次采访报告）
What was the purpose of carving out the flesh
在受害者死后 从她身上割下一块肉
after the victim's death?
是什么目的呢？
It looks like you'll have homework tonight.
看来你今晚要加班了
Still thinking about Hwang Dae-sun?
还在想黄大善吗？
You know me.
你知道我的
Let's start.
开始吧
Serial murders can be defined by these three things.
连环杀人犯有这三个特点
A psychological cooling-off period.
心理冷静期
Crime against a stranger to commit murder.
选择陌生人实施谋杀
Murdering three or more people, in three or more locations.
在三个或更多地点谋杀三个或更多人
Out of all the prisoners we've met,
在我们遇到的所有犯人里
Hwang Dae-sun is closest
黄大善最符合
to the serial killer category we are researching.
我们正在研究的连环杀手类别
He did kill three people,
他杀了三个人
But he killed them
可如果认真来看的话 他的作案地点
in two different cases. He killed one out of impulse.
是两个不同地方 其中一个人是计划之外的
He may have planned the murder,
他可能预谋好了谋杀计划
but it wasn't part of his initial plan.
可现实偏离了他最初的计划
I see two were raped and then murdered, and the other was a man.
我看其中两个人是先奸后杀 另外一个是男人
He had been drinking when committing both cases.
两次作案时他都喝了酒
The man was the second victim's boyfriend.
那个男人是第二个受害者的男友
Then the boyfriend was murdered out of impulse?
这个男友是计划之外的？
Exactly.
没错
On his way to his girlfriend's house, he witnessed the rape
他去女友家时 看到了强奸过程
and was murdered.
于是被杀
All three victims were murdered under the influence.
三个受害者均是酒后被杀
So it's an unsystematic crime.
所以这是非系统性犯罪
Just because he was under the influence
他是酒后状态
doesn't mean that it was an unsystematic crime.
并不能证明这就是非系统性犯罪
An unsystematic crime
非系统性犯罪
is when confused behavior is shown during the crime.
是指作案时出现不解行为
In the case of Hwang Dae-sun, we can interpret his acts of
在黄大善案中 我们可以把他的
binding and carving out the skin as abnormal sexual behaviors.
捆绑和切割肉体行为视为异常性行为
So it doesn't add up perfectly.
所以它并不完全符合
If you look at it according to the FBI's categories of crime,
如果你根据 美国联邦调查局的犯罪类型来看
a systematic type is someone who has personality issues.
系统性凶手是有性格缺陷的人
An unsystematic type
非系统性凶手
is someone delusional or schizophrenic.
是妄想症或精神分裂症患者
With that in mind, Hwang Dae-sun
这么看来 黄大善
isn't someone who has a mental illness
不是有精神疾病的人
but a systematic type with a personality disorder.
而是有人格缺陷的系统性凶手
This is difficult.
好难
In the case of Dae-sun, he showed systematic behavior
黄大善的案子里 他搜索和处理受害者时
in how he searched and dealt with victims using tools.
使用工具的方式表现为系统性行为
I understand when you tell me.
你们给我讲的时候我能理解
But the process of reasoning is always difficult.
可是推理的过程太难了
All right then.
因此
I think the reason Hwang Dae-sun's case is a serial one
我认为黄大善案是连环案的理由是
is this one. Killing more than three.
这一条 杀害三人以上
Okay.
是
But I think it's more accurate to label it as a rape and murder case
可我觉得更准确的分类是
with continuity.
连续性的强奸谋杀案
Since he had a sexual purpose to it.
因为他有性目的
Right, but there was a bigger chance of him becoming
对 不过如果他没有被捕 有很大可能
a serial killer if he hadn't been caught.
会成为连环杀手
I was shocked when I heard he'd killed animals as a kid.
听到他小时候杀死动物时我都震惊了
It's a classic feature that serial killers have.
那是连环杀手的典型特征
But he didn't have a cooling-off period.
可是他没有冷静期
A PSYCHOLOGICAL COOLING-OFF PERIOD
（心理冷静期）
The culprit behind the Suseong-dong
10日在江南区寿城洞
murder case of the old couple in their sixties
一对六十多岁老夫妇遇害
in Gangnam on the 10th has yet to be caught.
此案的幕后真凶还没有被抓到
People are shocked after the victim was identified
受害者身份曝光是韩国大学教授
as Hankuk University's Professor Han Seok-hoon and his wife.
韩世勋及其妻子 让民众大为震惊
Not only did Professor Han teach economics at the university,
韩教授不仅在大学教授经济
but he also appeared on TV often to give his economical insights.
还经常在电视露面发表对经济的看法
His bold attitude led to his popularity.
他的大胆态度也让他颇受欢迎
But does there always have to be a cooling-off period?
可是心理上的冷静期一定存在吗？
Serial killers feel
连环杀手
the highest form of pleasure in the pure act of killing.
可以在单纯的杀戮中 感受到最高程度的愉悦
Once the pleasure ends, they search for a new victim.
一旦愉悦结束 他们会搜寻新的受害者
To put it simply, a cooling-off period
简单来说 冷静期
is a period where their sense of satisfaction
就是他们从谋杀中获得的满足感
from the murder continues to last.
持续的阶段
Once that psychological satisfaction comes to an end,
一旦心理上的满足感结束
they'll move on to the next murder.
他们就会开始下一场谋杀
Then what about Hwang Dae-sun?
那么黄大善呢？
In the case of Hwang Dae-sun,
在黄大善案中
we can't view those periods as a cooling-off period
我们不能把那些阶段视为冷静期
since he was under the influence during all the crimes.
因为他的所有犯罪都是酒后进行的
But the fact that they murder again once the period ends
他们在一个阶段结束后还会继续谋杀
is so horrifying.
这个太可怕了
Thankfully, in Korea,
幸好在韩国
there haven't been any murder cases
还没有出现任何
with the purpose of murder and a cooling-off period.
以谋杀为目的而且有冷静期的谋杀案
It's all just speculation.
这只是猜测
These guys are the reason you said you'd need ten years, right?
你说需要十年 就是要对付这些家伙 对吗？
You said you didn't find
你说你没有在
any injuries on the back of them, right?
背部发现任何伤痕 是吗？
Right, I didn't find any.
对 什么都没有
It looks clean, right?
看起来很干净 对吧？
Drop me off at the office, please.
把我送去办公室吧
You're not going home?
你不回去吗？
No, I want to organize my thoughts.
不 我想理理思路
You can head home first. Good job today.
你先回去吧 今天辛苦了
No, I want to stop by Gangnam Police Station.
不 我想去江南区警察局一趟
I heard it's a mess over there right now.
听说那里现在一团糟
SCIENTIFIC INVESTIGATIONS TEAM
（现场鉴定组）
Which team was Gangnam's Professor Han case handed over to?
江南区韩教授的案子交给哪个组了？
Special Crime Squad's Team Two.
机搜队二组
Hello?
喂？
Yes.
是
Footprints?
脚印？
Yes, all right. I'll get back to you.
是 好的 我稍后联系你
It's Jongno Police Station.
是钟路区警察局
The Gungok-dong case they sent in last week…
上周送来的郡谷洞案
They want us to run footprints
他们想让我们把脚印
and other evidence via the ex-convict database.
和其他证据上传到历史案件数据库
-Shall I bring them over? -Yes.
-要我把那些带来吗？ -是
SUSEONG-DONG CASE FOOTPRINTS
（寿城洞案 脚印）
-Here you go. -Thanks.
-给你 -谢谢
What?
什么？
What is it?
怎么了？
Don't these look similar?
看起来是不是很像？
I think they do.
我觉得是一样的
You finally managed to finish the report.
你终于忙完那个案子了
-Congratulations. -Thank you.
-辛苦了 -谢谢你
HWANG DAE-SUN SECOND INTERVIEW REPORT
（黄大善二次采访报告）
Good job. Let's go now.
辛苦了 我们走吧
You can head home.
你们先回去吧
I'm behind on a lot of work because of this report.
因为这个报告 好多工作都落下了
My gosh, you're unbelievable.
天啊 你是真狠
What's the word for this? Workahill?
那个词怎么说来着？工作什么？
-It's "holic." -A workaholic.
-工作狂
I'll get going.
我走了
Chu Chu, how about a glass of soju and beer?
宇宙宙 一起来杯烧啤怎么样？
Sounds great!
太好了
-Good luck. -All right. Bye.
-加油 -好 再见
-Bye! -Bye.
-再见
GUNGOK-DONG FAMILY MURDER CASE SEPTEMBER 24, 2003
（郡谷洞全家被杀案 2003年9月24号）
UNIDENTIFIED WEAPON
（不明钝器）
Both victims do not have
两名受害者
any defense marks or signs of resistance.
都没有防御伤痕或抵抗痕迹
The culprit beat the victims without giving them a moment…
凶手直接击倒受害者 都没有给他们
to protect themselves.
任何自卫的机会
GUNGOK-DONG
（郡谷洞）
A type of systematic crime…
按计划实施的
committed according to a plan.
系统性犯罪类型
The crime is too cruel and daring to conclude
罪行过于残忍
that it was done by an acquaintance.
不敢断定是熟人作案
JINJUNG-DONG, GANGNAM
（江南区晋中洞）
The culprit did not take…
凶手没有带走
any money or valuables.
任何现金或贵重物品
Who is it?
谁啊？
DISGUISED AS ROBBERY
（伪装成盗窃）
COMMITTED OUT OF GRUDGE?
（实施仇杀？）
-Who is it? -Is somebody here?
-谁啊？ -有人来吗？
Yes, but I don't hear anything.
是 可是我什么都没听到
It must be a prank.
一定是恶作剧
Goodnight.
晚安
That's odd. Okay. Goodnight.
真奇怪 好 晚安
PRESUMED AS AN ACQUAINTANCE
（推断是熟人）
But is there someone who is an ex-convict around Professor Han?
可是韩教授周围有前科犯吗？
Is this a way of expressing…
是凶手因为仇恨
the culprit's emotions caused by a grudge they hold?
而泄愤的杀人方式吗？
GUNGOK-DONG, JONGNO
（钟路区郡谷洞）
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
（正在调查 禁止进入）
15 GUNGOK-DONG
（郡谷洞15号）
SONG YOUNG-CHUL, LEE GEUM-SOON
（宋永哲 李锦顺）
CASE REPORT
（案件报告）
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Coming to work now?
现在才上班吗？
Yes.
对
What happened at the crime scene yesterday?
昨天在案发现场发生了什么？
I thought you weren't interested.
我以为你没兴趣管呢
Are you actually curious? I'll tell you once we're inside.
你真想了解吗？进去我会告诉你的
You got a lot bolder, Tae-gu.
你的胆子越来越大了 泰九
You still have that feisty charm.
还是以前那种强硬的魅力
I do not want your evaluation of my charms.
我不想要你来评价我的魅力
I hope we can just carry out our duties
我希望我们各自履行职责
without getting in each other's way.
不要互相干扰
You know how important teamwork is when it comes to violent crimes.
你知道处理重案时 团队合作有多重要吗？
How can you only do your duty?
你怎么能只履行自己的职责呢？
Tae-gu,
尹泰九
do you still have a grudge against me?
你还在恨我吗？
A grudge?
恨？
You're quite delusional.
你的错觉还真严重
I do not have anything against you.
我对你没有任何其他感情
I'm sorry about that.
对不起了
But everyone already knows
不过大家都知道
that I'm the bastard.
我是混蛋
Right?
对吧？
I was also aware of
我也知道
how you were a bastard too.
你有多混蛋
Isn't that so?
是吗？
Let's go inside.
请进吧
I should not stop the ace of the Special Crime Squad.
我可不能挡了机搜队主力的路
Shall I, then?
那我可以走了吗？
Gosh, heartburn.
天啊 真心痛
You still think you can do this job by keeping loyalty
在这里干三年了 你还觉得靠着忠诚
even after spending three years here?
就能做好这份工作吗？
What should I do with you?
我该拿你怎么办啊？
You know how strict Detectives Kang and Park are.
你知道江刑警和朴刑警有多严格
I'm sure Moo-sik
我敢肯定林武植
won't get any information from them anymore.
不会再从他们那儿拿到任何信息了
Detective Park isn't the only detective there.
那里不是只有朴刑警一个人
If anyone leaks intel to Daehan Daily,
如果有人给《大韩日报》泄密
it all turns into Moo-sik's article,
都会进入林武植的报道
while you're sitting around depending on Detective Park.
你还坐在那里眼巴巴等着朴刑警
Moo-sik
林武植前辈
even steals articles from juniors?
还会从后辈那里偷报道？
Man, talk about lack of conscience.
真是没有良知啊
Yes, conscience.
对 良知
That won't put food on the table.
你为了那破良心想饿死吗？
I've been running around a lot trying not to starve to death.
我一直跑来跑去不就是为了不饿死嘛
Sure. You work so hard.
对 你工作那么努力
You're commendable, aren't you?
真的是可爱死了
My boss is doing a great job at making me slave away.
还不是因为我的老板会使唤我
Forget it.
算了
Go out and find an item that is as good a story
赶紧出去 找一个跟你被偷那篇故事
as the one you got stolen.
一样好的新闻
What do you mean? It wasn't ours anyway.
这是什么意思？ 那个本来就不是我们的
It's Detective Park.
是朴刑警
Another case at Gangnam Police Station broke out.
江南警察局辖区也出现了一个案子
-Again? -Yes.
-又有了？ -是的
Hey, Reporter Choi, keep it up. Run!
喂 崔记者 加把劲 跑起来
Forget all about your conscience and loyalty!
忘了你的良知和忠诚
Reporter Choi, get us just one good story!
崔记者 咬住一个也行
Keep up the good work, then.
大家继续工作吧
Man, I like how big this office is.
真是的 我就喜欢这种宽敞的办公室
Are you satisfied with your first order on the job?
你很满意自己下的第一个命令吗？
Captain Kook put a lot of effort into making those.
国组长为了做这个费了多大劲啊
If it just sits there,
如果放在这里
think how awkward he'll feel.
想想看他得多尴尬
So what will they do with all that information?
那么多文件他们想怎么处理？
No idea.
不知道
He'll use it as his pillow or something.
可能会拿来做枕头吧
I'm sure Captain Kook
我相信国组长
will make good use of everything.
给他什么东西都能好好利用的
Make sure you check and take everything as needed!
一定要仔细检查一个不漏 认真取证
-Yes, sir.
-知道了
-In-tak. -Hey, Young-soo.
-仁卓 -荣秀
Is something going on?
出什么事了吗？
Gangnam Station needed backup. We're heading to Jinjung-dong.
江南警察局需要支援 我们准备去晋中洞
What about you?
你呢？
I have to check some footprints.
我要去检查脚印
I see. Keep it up.
知道了 继续努力
-Okay. -Wait.
-好 -等等
To your office, right?
这是要去你办公室吧？
-I'm fine. Get back to work. -I'll go with you.
-我可以的 你去忙吧 -我跟你一起去
Hey, I'm still going strong.
喂 我硬朗着呢
Just get back to work.
赶紧回去忙工作吧
-Seriously? -Bye.
-确定吗？ -再见
-Are you sure? -Yes.
-确定
If you get stuck, feel free to bring it to us.
如果你遇到难题就来找我们
-Bye. -Be careful!
-再见 -小心点
-Yes, there. -Newsflash.
-对 那里 -新闻快报
This afternoon in Jinjung-dong, Gangnam,
今天下午 在江南区晋中洞
a woman in her fifties was found dead after being struck by a blunt weapon.
发现一具50多岁的女性尸体 死因为钝器打击
The police were dispatched for an investigation
保姆李某在受害者家中 发现倒在地上的受害者
after a report made by Lee, the maid,
于是立即报案
who saw the collapsed victim in her home.
随后警察前往现场调查
Gangnam Police Station said the culprit of today's
江南警察局声称今天
Jinjung-dong and the Suseong-dong incident are…
晋中洞案的凶手和寿城洞案是…
Chief Heo, what on earth is going on?
许队长 这到底是怎么回事？
I told you to investigate this quietly. Why is it blowing up?
我跟你说过要悄悄调查 怎么爆出来了？
Captain Yoon and Detective Nam are at the scene right now.
尹组长和南刑警已经在现场了
-Let's hear from them once they return. -Good grief.
-等他们回来听听怎么说吧 -天啊
Where's Kim Bong-sik?
金奉植呢？
No idea. But he'll crawl back
不知道 不过如果他知道这会影响
if he thinks this will affect his performance.
他的绩效的话 爬也要爬回来的
That's his deal.
他就是那种人
Look at how big this case has become.
看看这案子变多大了
We might end up taking over
我们可能最后两个案子
both of these cases.
都要接了
Tell me about it.
可不是嘛
These reporters already began to say that they're related or something.
记者们已经开始说它们有关联之类的
I have a bad feeling about this.
我有不好的预感
We can't let this happen.
不能让那种事发生啊
Okay. Who is it?
好了 谁啊？
Excuse me.
前辈
Hey.
你好
-Hello.
-你好
What brings you here?
你怎么来了？
I found something weird.
我发现了一些奇怪的地方
-I wanted your opinion on this. -What is it?
-我想听听你的意见 -这是什么？
-Both are hiking shoes. -Yes.
-两双都是登山鞋 -是
What about them?
那怎么了？
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
这个是在江南区寿城洞
And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno.
这个是在钟路区郡谷洞
They match, right?
但是看起来一样 对吧？
They're from different areas but the same culprit?
所在辖区不同 但是是同一个凶手？
A LUXURIOUS RESIDENTIAL HOUSE IN GUNGOK-DONG
（郡谷洞一处豪宅）
My mom cooked breakfast for me. I ate it and went to work.
我妈给我做了早饭 我吃完就上班了
When I called, she didn't answer.
我给她打电话 没人接
So I came home and…
我就回家了 然后…
Did anyone hold grudges against her?
她有仇人吗？
Or did she have any money problems?
或者有经济纠纷？
None.
都没有
Did she ever sound upset on the phone?
她打电话时有没有情绪低沉？
No.
没有
Hey.
喂
What? There was another case in Jinjung-dong.
什么？晋中洞又有一个案子
-What? -Look at this.
-什么？ -看这个
I'm reading it now.
我正在看
"A woman living in her fifties in Jinjung-dong was found dead
“在晋中洞 发现一名50多岁的女性尸体
from blunt force trauma."
死因为钝器打击”
UNIDENTIFIED BLUNT WEAPON
（不明钝器）
-So was the victim in Gungok-dong. -Right?
-郡谷洞受害者也是一样 -是吗？
I'll check out the scene.
我要去现场检查
I'm going to the Special Crime Squad.
我要去机搜队
As the media says, this case has similarities
像媒体说的一样 这个案子
to Professor Han's case.
和韩教授案有相似之处
What? Then it wasn't a revenge killing?
什么？那这不是仇杀？
We'll have to investigate more,
我们还要再调查
but we don't have any suspects in Professor Han's case.
不过韩教授案还没查到任何嫌疑人
They both died
他们都死于
from blunt force trauma to the head.
头部的钝器创伤
And it was staged as a robbery?
伪装成盗窃？
Yes.
是
Gil-pyo. Chief.
吉票 组长
Hey, we're busy. Come back later.
喂 我们正忙着呢 等会儿再来
-Check this out now. -Come back later.
-快看这个 -等会儿再来
Just look at this.
看看这个
Hiking shoes.
登山鞋
What about them?
这怎么了？
In-tak brought them to me.
仁卓带给我的
The first is from Suseong-dong. The second is from Gungok-dong.
第一个是寿城洞的 第二个是郡谷洞
Suseong-dong is in Gangnam. Gungok-dong is in Jongno.
寿城洞在江南区 郡谷洞在钟路区
-Give me that. -It's the same guy.
-给我看下 -是同一个人
I read the reports. It's the same MO.
我看了报告 作案手法一样
-Blunt force trauma? -Yes. Exactly.
-钝器创伤？ -是 没错
Suseong-dong and Gungok-dong. They were hit in the head.
寿城洞和郡谷洞 他们都是头部受伤
The victim in Jinjung-dong also died from--
晋中洞的受害者也死于…
You knew?
你知道了？
I just got back
我刚从
from the crime scene in Jinjung-dong.
晋中洞案发现场回来
Who on earth is this guy?
这家伙到底是谁？
The MO is the same.
作案手法都一样
Why are you here?
你怎么来了？
Let me in.
让我进去
You're not an investigator. Why?
你不是调查人员 凭什么让你进？
-I need to see the crime scene. -Leave!
-我要看案发现场 -走开
Don't try to steal my case. Get lost!
别想偷我的案子 快走开
Please. I must check the crime scene.
拜托了 我一定要检查案发现场
Hey. Didn't you hear me?
喂 你没听见吗？
I told you to get lost, you bastard!
我让你走开 混蛋
Damn it.
该死
This is important.
这事非常重要
The victim was hit by a blunt weapon.
受害者遭钝器打击
UNIDENTIFIED BLUNT WEAPON
（不明钝器）
There are no footsteps in the bedroom.
卧室没有脚印
And the safe wasn't touched either.
保险箱也没有碰过
CRIME SCENE STEPPING PLATES
（犯罪现场通行板）
There's no trace of blood splattered on the ceiling.
天花板没有溅上血迹
It means…
也就是说…
the culprit subdued the victim with one blow.
凶手只用一次就击倒了受害者
-Yes. -Are you there?
-是 -你到现场了？
What do we do?
我们该怎么办？
I thought we had ten years.
我以为我们还有十年
But it happened too quickly.
可是这么快就发生了
This killer checks all the boxes.
这个凶手符合所有条件
1. A PSYCHOLOGICAL COOLING-OFF PERIOD
（一 心理冷静期）
2. CRIME AGAINST A STRANGER TO COMMIT MURDER
（二 选择陌生人实施谋杀）
3. MURDERING THREE OR MORE PEOPLE IN THREE OR MORE LOCATIONS
（三 在三个或更多地点 谋杀三个或更多人）
The police admitted the recent killings in wealthy neighborhoods
警方承认最近在富人区发生的谋杀案
could have been part of a serial killing.
可能是连环杀人案
The police will consider the three murder cases
警方将发生在江南区和钟路区的
in Gangnam and Jongno as serial murder cases
三起谋杀案视为连环杀人案
and do their best to find the culprit
并将向这些地区
by dispatching more resources to these areas.
派遣更多警力 尽全力抓获凶手
There have been murder cases in Suseong-dong and Jinjung-dong,
在江南区寿城洞和晋中洞接连
back to back.
发生谋杀案
And between these two cases, a similar murder case
这两起案件发生期间 在钟路区郡谷洞
took place in Gungok-dong, Jongno-gu.
也发生了一起相似案件
And the late discovery of the news has put the residents in fear.
近期发生的这些案件让居民陷入恐惧
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
（正在调查 禁止进入）
The culprit went to different areas,
凶手在不同地点流窜
and his only purpose was to kill.
他的唯一目的就是杀人
This is the third murder.
这是第三起谋杀案
Please do not cross.
请不要越线
What happened here?
这里怎么了？
It's a serial murder.
这是一个连环杀人案
A woman in her sixties was found dead in a residential area in Hwanghwa-dong.
在黄花洞一处居民区 发现一名60多岁的女性尸体
The police launched an investigation.
警方展开调查
-A blunt weapon was used. -The triangle again?
-是钝器 -又是三角形？
Something is off. I'm sure he came across an unexpected situation.
好像哪里不对劲 他肯定遇到了意外情况
You guys in the Analysis Team should return to the office.
你们分析小组的人应该回办公室去
Entering the crime scene as they please is obstructing the investigation.
随意进入案发现场是妨碍调查
The answers are always found at the scene.
答案总是在现场找到的
-What are we supposed to do with that? -We can buy time.
-我们该怎么处理这个？ -我们可以争取时间
Don't tell me you're buying this nonsense.
别跟我说你会信这种说辞
The only way to prevent him from committing the next murder…
阻止他犯下新的谋杀案的唯一方法…
is this.
只有这个